Yun Gu

software engineer +44 7536347095 GuY36@cardiff.ac.uk http://yungu.vercel.app Cardiff, CF24

EXPERTISE

I am a designer as well as a developer aiming to make design and codes cleaner. I'm experienced in the full UX Design lifecycle and working in an agile environment (Scrum). Besides, I'm familiar with Tailwind CSS, React & Vue, and Git.

EDUCATION

Cardiff University

Master's degree Software Engineering with a professional placement year 2021-2023

Shanghai Maritime University

Bachelor's degree (2:1) Electronic Information Engineering 2017-2021

SKILLS

Programming languages:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, Java, C++, Python.

Libraries & Frameworks:

React, Vue, Tailwind CSS, Node.js.

Design:

Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Sketch, Axure.

Tools & Platforms:

Miro, Jira, Maze, Gitlab, Jenkins, Terraform, OpenStack, Slack, Teams.

Languages:

English, Chinese (Mandarin).

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer @ Cardiff University

July 2022 - July 2023, 1 year | Cardiff

- > Main roles: responsible for the entire lifecycle from whiteboard to delivery
- design research (interviews, testing, etc.), service design (diagrams,
- blueprints, etc.), and interaction design (wireframes, prototyping, etc.). > Involved projects: Student App (e.g., find a library, COIVD tests booking),
- Internal Management Systems (e.g., Identity management system, Extenuating circumstances reports, external users request IT access), Design Systems of Cardiff University.
- > Tools used: Figma (design, prototype), Miro (diagrams, whiteboard, etc.), Jira (organisation, project management), Maze (testing), Slack (communication), Notion (Spreadsheets).
- > Work with: Users (student & staff), Developers, Business Analysts, and other related teams.
- > Technology stack of the team: React and Tailwind CSS.
- > Enhanced the concept of User-Centered Design, and Agile development.

UX + Front-end Developer @ 51Job

July 2020-September 2020, 3 months | Shanghai

- > Communicated with clients (e.g., Coco-Cola, AMD) for their commands, designed and developed the recruiting websites independently or with colleagues.
- > Technology used: Vue, Adobe Illustrator, Axure.

Data Analyst Assistant @ Zyllion Data

February 2020-April 2020, 2 months | Shanghai

- > Collected data using a web crawler in Python.
- > Technologies used: Regular Expression, Tencent Sheet.

PROJECTS

Master courses work

websites for a charity (design, agile development, frontend, backend, and DevOps)

Undergraduate final project

Android application for a wearable EEG headset (fetch data via Bluetooth, visualise on the app in real-time)

More projects on my Online portfolio (React, Tailwind CSS, Next.js, Vercel)